Namaskar Welcome to Lunar Astro
Today's topic is Mercury
In today's topic we will learn how to perform these
remedial parts and what are the biological effects in our
body how those remedies which are told to you of different
plants how they affect biologically and how our biological
changes provide us with
intelligence
Along with that in today's video we will learn that
whenever a remedial part is done what are the side effects
and proper effects whenever you do any work in nature and
this is Mercury's part how sensitive you are some people
are very insensitive because
they have lost their own feelings there is no compunction
along with that they don't want to understand anyone else's
feelings in such people's third house third house is how
fast you react, over react or under react people say in
classical texts
Mars, Rahu they work very well in any malefic third house
they work very well and the reason is the era in which that
book is written you have to fight in that era you have to
fight day and night for food security, land security and
there intelligence
has a limited value after that your body has strength
you have to be insensitive to understand but if your work
is based on intelligence in today's world the more
intelligent a person is the less anger he gets he reacts
less he understands other people he talks like a human
there are benefits in third house
when there are benefits in third house painters become
poets astrologers because in this profession all these
professions which are extremely sensitive you have to be
very sensitive
but when there are malefics like Mars, Saturn, Rahu, Ketu
such malefics even transit you see it becomes very
straightforward
I don't care who is doing what
I am done with all these people
and because of that a person becomes insensitive
when malefics transit a person becomes insensitive whereas
benefits make a person sensitive you will see our thyroid
gland which is in the shape of a butterfly which is in the
third house similarly our ears third house we can hear so
well we like good
music what to say our subconscious brain chooses words,
designs patterns and how creative we can be everything is
in the third house always remember this if you see
someone's house minimalistic in design you will understand
that in the third house there
is a planet which promotes minimal designs the more
classical designs you see the more you will understand music
the music in 16 string sitar and the technical music
you will start to understand the difference the more
refined you become that is the effect of the third house
there is a study it says that a person has extreme trouble
the root cause of trouble is that the bacteria in the gut
does not function properly
the gut biome is not good if the gut biome is not good the
number one reason is stress when we are stressed our
stomach does not function properly mercury has only two
houses the third house we can hear we can hear we can hear
and the second house is
the lower abdomen when the person does not have the
bacteria in the gut there is a music video for 8 minutes
due to which the hormones relax the bacteria performs and
because of that the person gets well the music heals you
you do not understand why you
are healed you are listening to those music pieces you have
to listen we are the most blessed generation you have
internet free you have so many classical music channels
different frequencies you have classical masterpieces which
were not available to
us 40 years ago
Pandit Jasraj
Pandit Harish Prasad Chaudhary
Pandit Bheem Shankar and their masterpieces which were sung
in 1980s are available on youtube when you start listening
your music choice will be different you will understand
where the epitome of music has come but what happens when
you listen when you
are listening well that is why mercury is a name when you
keep on listening to your name something gets activated
there is sludging in cricket why do batsmen get affected by
sludging? because you react to something
third house when you are listening to music when you are
speaking that is why play music at home play raga bhairavi
play raga bhopali when it is evening play any raga and
second thing when you feel like reciting shiva sahasranaam
like all the remedies
of mercury if you read in shastras you will see that it is
said different types of remedies there is music
shahasranaam of mercury is the best remedy there is a
shloka it is said if jupiter is in 2nd or 7th house such a
person will always be in distress
and to get rid of distress such a person should recite
shiva sahasranaam but if there is a satan aspect this is my
interpretation which I have seen practically in people's
charts if there is a satan aspect then one should recite
shiva sahasranaam if there
is a shukra aspect then one should recite lalita
sahasranaam people used to say in earlier times that we
have this thing in our throat the meaning of that after
many years few days back
I understood what is actually in throat because you
remember how does the throat know that there is no memory
in the throat but what happens when you remember such a
difficult path ugram viram vishwa sahasranaam lalita
sahasranaam you recite rudraksh
chakram you will come to know one thing that throat has to
be trained for particular sounds for particular pauses you
have to bring the volume up you have to bring the volume
down you have to give pause for which sound because there
are many holes in
the sound how will your pronunciation come for that your
throat has to be trained what happens when throat is
trained you should think what a brilliant remedy has been
given scientists are saying after listening to this 8
minute video gut biome gets cured
food gets digested our sages used to think much more they
used to say the whole world gets cured
I saw a video where they were talking about manifestation
and they were laughing and saying
I want this, I want that and I realized we recite this
daily if you will recite purushottam the last three lines
it is said the last three lines it is said
I want everything so when you are doing this manifestation
when you are doing prayers what happens the thyroid gland
which controls other hormones basically the butterfly which
is said in Vedas basically its parallel version is in our
throat so when you
say The more you are preparing, the more you are able to
train it, the more you are able to contest it, the more
your world starts changing.
I will tell you the reason for that.
Now I have realized...
Many times your realizations are at different levels.
And as you keep reading, you feel that you didn't know this
before.
At least I didn't know this.
So I am telling you to start reading.
So what will happen?
The thyroid will be activated from here.
What will happen because of that part?
The gut's biome will be activated.
Because you are reading something like this, you are
chanting something like this.
And you are chanting properly.
Because of that, the gut's bacteria will change.
When the gut's bacteria changes, it will digest the food
that has been eaten by sin.
Because all the sin is in the food.
And that food is in your body.
That is what is giving you the disease.
So when your gut's bacteria, which is Ketu, is activated,
after that, the body's gut is digested.
Your brain's configuration changes.
And you will see that when the brain's configuration
changes, you will feel very sleepy.
You will realize that you don't want to do this anymore.
Because now your brain's circuits are changing.
The way you think is changing the way you think.
Because now your gut's bacteria is changing.
There is a Scottish saying,
The word God has come from the gut.
Gut is God.
Now you understand why the gut is God.
Why Ketu is the cause of liberation.
We all have read that Ketu is the cause of liberation.
Why? There can be multiple reasons.
Now I understand.
When Ketu is activated in the stomach, in the gut,
Why was Ketu given the 6th house in the Red Book?
That was the house of Buddha.
Ketu was given the 6th house in that.
Because when Ketu is activated in the gut, which I say,
don't do anything in your life.
I say, eat probiotics daily.
When you are eating probiotics, you digest your gut.
You have to do one chant daily.
You have to sit and read properly.
Even if it is for 2.5 minutes or 3 minutes.
But you have to sit in the gut.
If you do Vishwa Satsang, you will see changes
automatically in your life.
When you start doing this, you will understand that because
of Ketu, you are getting liberation.
Ketu is governing you.
It is directing you not to do this work.
Scientists say that the person who has a bad gut, does not
develop love hormones.
Why? Because such a person cannot love anyone.
He has irritability.
That's why, look at the remedy part.
It is said to give curd for Venus.
Venus has nothing to do with curd.
Because it is made of bacteria.
It is a fermented item.
It is an item of Ketu.
Why is it being fed?
Because when Ketu goes inside the stomach, all the hatred
in your gut, will cool down.
Your gut bacteria will improve.
Then you will be able to love someone.
The irritation inside you will end.
Now, you think about it as much as you want.
I saw that you tell someone that your Ketu is not good.
It is not good.
You have Ketu trouble.
Do one thing.
Eat curd.
That person will tell you that he eats curd daily.
I have done this.
Recently, I was doing a simulation.
Venus and Ketu were three in Navamsa.
Second marriage.
The second marriage also broke.
Venus is the Lagna Lord of Navamsa.
He is the 9th house Rahu.
He is neither a father nor a boss.
He is a Guru.
It is difficult to give consultation to such a person.
I said,
I have to do your consultation.
You have come through a reference.
You will not benefit from the consultation.
The rest is up to you.
Whatever you say to such a person, it will be difficult for
him to understand.
You are saying a very simple thing.
You have to eat curd regularly.
Why? Venus is with Ketu.
These two are not compatible in Navamsa.
These two plants are opposite plants.
But what is the remedial part of Lal Gita?
You eat curd for Venus.
As you eat curd, the person will improve the gut bacteria
in life.
His heart will open.
And the person will reduce hate.
He will love more.
Whenever you go to the remedial parts of Mercury, keep in
mind, there are two remedies.
Why skin issues?
There is irritation inside.
Pitta has increased.
If the Kapha gets spoiled, it will also get stuck in it.
Whenever there is excess Pitta in the gut, because it is a
part of the body, it goes to the gut.
When Pitta increases so much, it will irritate inside.
It will burn you on the outside.
So, you understand, your Mercury has increased by more than
35%.
You don't know how to listen to music.
You don't know how to speak nicely to anyone.
You don't have the taste of your surroundings.
If you talk about chart and weather in the day, you
understand, and if you feel the weather, because again,
sensitivity, like we talked about in the beginning.
You know from Namit, from action, what is going to happen
in today's day.
If this has happened, then this is going to happen.
This intuition, this is also a third house, that you know
how to catch signs.
And when you catch these small things, your conscious level
increases.
For example,
I will give you a very small example.
I went to get my hair cut twice in the last week.
Twice.
The person in front of me said, we don't have a slot
available.
You can't do anything in it.
And then I realized,
Saturn has a differential action.
Saturn is very strong.
You can't put it in now.
You have to bear with it.
Just learn how to bear with Saturn.
And after that, someone sent me a notification, in which I
am thinking, and it is written in front, that Saturn wants
you to train.
And it was a post.
The more you observe, the more your conscious level
increases.
The better your prediction is.
Because now you can understand the chart, catch it, and
understand its results, cause and effects.
From there you can backtrack it.
Because whenever Mercury is bad, such a person has no
control over his tongue.
No control over his speech.
Such a person doesn't know, what to say and where to say.
For example, if Mercury is in Aries or Scorpio sign, which
is a Martian sign, such a person will be highly logical.
He will speak with a lot of speed.
He will speak with logic.
He has a lot of fire energy.
Mercury and Scorpio are muted.
Muted means, two way meanings.
Wrong place, wrong thing.
You shouldn't say what you want to say.
Mercury is in Aries and Scorpio.
Venus is good for Mercury.
Venus can sit with Venus.
When Mercury comes with Saturn, such a person becomes
extremely calculative.
His way of thinking is extremely slow.
He is slow, but he has to give a final finish.
He has to think long term.
He will give a base in his voice.
And when you get such a voice, when you put your fingers on
your ears, suppose, in the 3rd house, with Mercury, a plant
has come, which is extremely fast moving.
For example, there is a show,
Friends.
The character is of Janus.
You will see, the character of Janus, the one who played,
used to make cartoon voices.
In their chart,
Mercury's combination is with Ketu.
With this combination, you will get such a voice.
You will get the base of the throat.
That is why you will see, as people move forward in
Sadhana, you will get to know from their voice, the depth
of this person.
Because, in a voice, there are many things.
Now, when we talk about Mercury and Ketu together,
Mercury is just after Ketu.
Now, you will understand, why Mercury is just after Ketu.
Because, Ketu's work is inside Mercury.
Your body, your lower abdomen, has bacteria inside it.
What does that bacteria do?
It gives you freedom.
And you will see, as your bacteria improves, your body's
biome improves, your biological levels improve, things
start happening in your life, which you did not think about.
Your way of thinking changes.
Your voice, it changes the way you speak even in choices if
you are not in a good mood, you will notice it in your
playlist in your choices and that is why you become
extremely moody you start realizing that I have to do this
work like this and that is
why I always say that
one day your life will be governed by
many of your bad decisions that what did you do today so
every morning when we do some work we think about its long
term impact is it taking me towards the life that I want to
live 5 years from now and if not, then I don't want to do
this work and the
more you bring clarity in your thought process the fewer
people you have in your life, the more priorities you have
and you know that you have to do this work like this and
that is why whenever you start doing remedial work for
mercury
I am telling you if you are suffering from
PCOD, thyroid, hormonal imbalance autism issues to an
extent along with that skin issues you have to start doing
remedial measures and remedial measures are very simple you
have to change your way of speaking you have to change your
way of thinking that
is why people say don't blame others don't do bad things to
others you have to look good you don't have to go to a show
or as a husband and wife or as a family member what do you
talk about technology, space, writers you tell stories or
you tell bad things about someone or you say this didn't
happen, that didn't happen that level of talk that level of
talk decides the
standard of your life and as you improve things around you
keep improving so learn to do this for mercury remedial
contest a lot of things sort out your life
I am making you insensitive don't do anything that you are
doing insensitively do that thing in which you are going
110% mercury has a speciality mercury's intelligence works
only with the plant mercury's company is important so when
you see a state where
mercury is seen as
Saturn and Mars that state mercury and people around you
will be like Saturn and Mars but let's suppose your state
is where mercury has benefit plants who sits around you if
there are dealers around you your mentality will be like
dealers if there are
people around you who have a positive mindset they think
what we are going to do next how we are going to progress
how we are going to help people eventually you will start
replicating them think carefully do I want to meet such
people do I want to do
such things because if you don't your way of thinking your
lifestyle, your habits will take you down so this was the
first video on mercury in the second video I want to
discuss a chart this chart is of Michelangelo the great
Michelangelo who made a lot
of paintings and scriptures according to the timeline what
happened in 1508, 1512 and how it is seen in the chart why
is the chart special what is there in the chart while
looking at the chart
I have met a lot of people
I meet 80-90% people if I am available always try to call
me what is interesting in the chart what will I learn
because I want to learn every chart teaches something new
there is something in every chart
I asked someone what does your father do does he make
chemicals or medicines he said he makes limestone why does
he make chemicals or medicines because in my mind there is
a combination of chemicals and medicines in D10 he said
limestone
I didn't understand the combination there was a boy from
Jharkhand in his chart
I always say
D10 is your career you will not be able to cross it in D10
the boy had a position of Sun Saturn and his dispositor was
in 6th house he used to see Mars this is the combination of
D10
I asked him who does the chemical work he said my father
does the metal work he cleans the metal from the chemicals
I asked him who does it he said my government job will not
work he said it will work on contractual basis he said I am
a contractual teacher do you know when all this is
happening when I am about to sit in my car and he is
showing me in his phone and
I am telling him this will come in your template it was
good that he brought his details so when you are doing this
when you see the chart everyday so for me what is special
in it are you doing the remedial part because many people
think my chart is special
every person is special one plant is special because they
remember their combinations like he saw someone's chart the
combination I asked him he said the landmark judgment of
supreme court is on me that judgment was given on me that
is why he takes reference
from all the courts so it is special so before that try to
improve yourself whether mercury has improved on you you
come to take consultation from panel even then try to
atleast do the mercury remedies because even a slodger will
need your good deeds
to give you the right direction if you do both then you
will get balance it is very difficult to get the right
guidance because 9th house is a brilliant house extremely
brilliant house but you have to be born with it bad or good
transit is going on depending
on there are people in your life who tell you only one line
like I told you today there are many things in one line but
the time span of learning one line is of many years
I teach further so when you progress yourself 9th house,
dashanth drekna someone sent me a very long article and
told me to calculate
I told him it is very simple this is my technique and it is
very simple in the chart of rich kids look at their charts
8th house is in combination with lagna e3 is in 8th house
or both are together Because they don't have to work hard
It's a very simple combination
It's one of many techniques
How did you learn this?
When you see a lot of charts continuously Then you will
realize that this kid will not have to work hard in life
And this happens in a good combination
Good combination means it will be beneficial
It won't be bad
It won't happen that Ketu and Mars are sitting together
If Ketu and Mars are there, of course he will work hard
And the hard work will go to a useless place
So I said
I have this small technique
You test on 100 charts
It will still work
You will get the exceptions to use it
You tell me
Which one of these is working
I will test that
I will use that
I don't have any objection
That Calculate cyclically
I will calculate
There is no problem
I have to make the software
But it should work
You tell me the technique
What is the practical application
Mercury Practical application
Does it work?
But I am looking at the Hora chart
I can see that it will become Arayapati
And I can't see it
So I need to calculate Hora chart in some other way
So We will end here
Look at the charts
Of actors, celebrities
People who are in such professions
Where You have to be extremely sensitive
And classy
You will understand
What is the importance of 3rd house
When malefic transit happens in 3rd house
You see the person's attitude
It gets cut
And benefits transit happens in 3rd house
You see
The person who goes from 3rd house to Jupiter
He becomes classy
Venus Mercury These are very simple combinations
So this was today's lecture
I will see you guys next time
Thank you
Bye Bye